[
  {
    "question": "Which of the following animals does Agnes Iron think of as 'diseased beasts'?",
    "a": "moose",
    "b": "foxes",
    "c": "oxen",
    "d": "rabbits",
    "e": "beavers",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why do people attend Bush's mourning feast despite doubting the authenticity of her ritual?",
    "a": "They respect the grief itself.",
    "b": "They fear she will place a curse on them.",
    "c": "They are desperate for a free meal.",
    "d": "They are greedy for her possessions.",
    "e": "They give in to Bush's constant wheedling.",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Bush gives away all of the following objects after her mourning feast EXCEPT her",
    "a": "rifle",
    "b": "hawk feathers",
    "c": "quilts",
    "d": "sleeping gown",
    "e": "sweater",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does the wild rice hold special significance at the mourning feast?",
    "a": "It represents the freedom to live independently.",
    "b": "The wild rice has a bitter flavor.",
    "c": "Angel was present when it was harvested.",
    "d": "Its name is also Angel's true name.",
    "e": "It signifies resistance to mechanized agriculture.",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the prologue, Agnes dreams of Hannah Wing appearing",
    "a": "below ground",
    "b": "on the riverbank",
    "c": "across the lake",
    "d": "under ice",
    "e": "in the sky",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "For returning Angel to Hannah Wing, Agnes blames",
    "a": "her daughter-in-law Bush",
    "b": "the state police",
    "c": "herself",
    "d": "her son Harold",
    "e": "the county government",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Before the mourning feast in the prologue, Bush had been arrested for stealing",
    "a": "furniture",
    "b": "sacks of onions",
    "c": "beaver pelts",
    "d": "fishing lures",
    "e": "fox snares",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "As Chapter 1 of Solar Storms opens, the population of Fur Island is",
    "a": "nine",
    "b": "one",
    "c": "three",
    "d": "five",
    "e": "seven",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "When Angel first writes to Agnes, she uses the last name",
    "a": "Smith",
    "b": "Doe",
    "c": "Jensen",
    "d": "Husk",
    "e": "Wing",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does Agnes send the money for Angel to travel to Adam's Rib in Chapter 1 of Solar Storms?",
    "a": "She includes a check in a care package.",
    "b": "She uses Western Union.",
    "c": "She mails physical one-dollar bills.",
    "d": "She arranges a wire payment through a bank.",
    "e": "She makes a deposit in Angel's ward account.",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Solar Storms, the men who abandoned the Abandoned Ones were",
    "a": "French",
    "b": "Norwegian",
    "c": "British",
    "d": "Indigenous",
    "e": "American",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does Dora-Rouge mistake Angel for Hannah Wing when they meet in Chapter 1 of Solar Storms?",
    "a": "Dora-Rouge is blind, and Agnes misleads her.",
    "b": "Dora-Rouge has entered a state of advanced dementia.",
    "c": "Angel has a strong physical resemblance to Hannah.",
    "d": "Angel's voice is almost exactly like Hannah's.",
    "e": "Angel walks the way Hannah used to.",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Angel is a blood relation of all of the following characters EXCEPT",
    "a": "Hannah Wing",
    "b": "Bush",
    "c": "Dora-Rouge Iron",
    "d": "Agnes Iron",
    "e": "Harold",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did Agnes let Harold leave with Loretta, according to Chapter 1 of Solar Storms?",
    "a": "Harold threatened Agnes with a shotgun.",
    "b": "Loretta threatened Agnes with a knife.",
    "c": "A flood threatened to sweep all of them away.",
    "d": "A fire threatened Agnes's home.",
    "e": "A lack of food threatened to starve them all.",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Solar Storms, the literature John Husk keeps shows his interest in",
    "a": "music",
    "b": "art",
    "c": "economics",
    "d": "science",
    "e": "mathematics",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does Angel’s family role change at the start of Chapter 2 of Solar Storms?",
    "a": "She had been single but becomes a wife.",
    "b": "She had been a ward but becomes a caretaker.",
    "c": "She had been an only child but becomes a sister.",
    "d": "She had been a daughter but becomes a mother.",
    "e": "She had been an orphan but regains a family.",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does Angel struggle to find work in Chapter 2 of Solar Storms?",
    "a": "The employers show disgust with Angel’s scarred face.",
    "b": "The employers display prejudice against Angel’s looks.",
    "c": "The employers want only strong men.",
    "d": "The employers find and circulate Angel’s criminal record.",
    "e": "The employers do not need employees.",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Agnes’s coat is made from the pelt of a",
    "a": "spectacled bear",
    "b": "glacier bear",
    "c": "polar bear",
    "d": "brown bear",
    "e": "moon bear",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did the bear lose its sanity while in Beauregard’s captivity?",
    "a": "Beauregard gouged out her eyes.",
    "b": "Beauregard murdered her cubs in front of her.",
    "c": "Beauregard kept her from finding a mate.",
    "d": "Beauregard fed her meat from other bears.",
    "e": "Beauregard did not let her hibernate.",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "How much did Beauregard’s men charge to view the bear for one minute?",
    "a": "a penny",
    "b": "a dime",
    "c": "a dollar",
    "d": "a nickel",
    "e": "a quarter",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Agnes steals back the bear pelt from Beauregard’s",
    "a": "daughter",
    "b": "business partner",
    "c": "son",
    "d": "widow",
    "e": "cousin",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 2 of Solar Storms, why does Agnes make macaroni and cheese on Fridays?",
    "a": "Dora-Rouge made a promise decades ago.",
    "b": "A Catholic visitor might come.",
    "c": "John Husk’s favorite meal is macaroni and cheese.",
    "d": "The poker game has two vegetarian players.",
    "e": "The act is part of Agnes’s promise to the bear she killed.",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "How did a foster mother lie to Angel about how Angel’s face became scarred?",
    "a": "The foster mother insisted Angel had had smallpox.",
    "b": "The foster mother told Angel she had been in a car accident.",
    "c": "The foster mother suggested that Angel had made her own scars.",
    "d": "The foster mother claimed Angel fell.",
    "e": "The foster mother said Angel had burned herself cooking.",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 3 of Solar Storms, Agnes serves the visitors all of the following foods EXCEPT",
    "a": "potatoes",
    "b": "bacon",
    "c": "rice",
    "d": "bread",
    "e": "eggs",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "The song Dora-Rouge teaches Angel in Chapter 4 of Solar Storms",
    "a": "calls animals",
    "b": "provides light",
    "c": "brings rain",
    "d": "lights fires",
    "e": "heals wounds",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which species of whale did a showman abandon in the Hungry Mouth of Water off Fur Island?",
    "a": "orca",
    "b": "pilot",
    "c": "beluga",
    "d": "right",
    "e": "minke",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1924, people discovered two children on Fur Island who had been raised by",
    "a": "wolves",
    "b": "otters",
    "c": "martens",
    "d": "beavers",
    "e": "foxes",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who ordered the destruction of the milkstone on Fur Island?",
    "a": "a chieftain",
    "b": "a bishop",
    "c": "a governor",
    "d": "a fur trader",
    "e": "a general",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "The walls of the Black House on Fur Island are made of",
    "a": "blackened lodgepole pine",
    "b": "shipwreck timber",
    "c": "obsidian",
    "d": "basalt rock",
    "e": "ballast stones",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 4 of Solar Storms, all of the following objects appear on Bush’s altar EXCEPT",
    "a": "tobacco",
    "b": "crosses",
    "c": "rosaries",
    "d": "pictures of Angel",
    "e": "eagle feathers",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  }
]